uh ready set yet another update video
here it is uh I'm relaxing it's my
birthday but I'm making yet another
pivot and people used to I used to get
my nickname is flipflop
Rob and somebody's going to call me that
and I'll just say okay fine um get ready
for a lot of changes they're on the
screen right now if you want to just
look at them really fast and not listen
to me explain them to you can finish
this video a lot faster uh but if you're
wondering what's changing and why and
what happened to the holiday boost and
where's the other boost going here is
the new information we have so before we
get going on this too much hey thank you
for the holiday wishes or the birthday
wishes um the reason I change is when I
get new information I'm going to tell
you what that new information is and why
it changes everything and why it's so
hard for me to finish anything
especially as a technologist in
education um the first thing is Discord
is better than slack so no slack we're
going to stay in Discord I'm going to
try to get to them more please join us
in the Discord if you don't know how you
know click on the Linker tree link you
can go click and find it do with that
okay so I did go in there I answered
some things that were in there uh
deleted some things that were totally
inappropriate and stupid I wish I had
been watching for um so I'm going to do
better at that so thank you for the link
um uh twitch RC I live in twitch RC
right now in fact I it's actually on
right now if I turn it back on uh you
can see it here so there's all the
things um and there's you know people
that are making stuff or they're saying
stuff in here and this is on all day so
whether I'm streaming or not whether I'm
at work or not that is on all day so
oopsie um why am I telling you this
because you can come in there and I
encourage you to come in there and get
all kinds of help in real time so it's
lonely you know it's lonely during the
day especially if you're a remote
employee come come join me it's not hard
uh if you don't know how to join IRC
you're still struggling I made a video
on it but I'm going to make it even
easier and I'm going to get to that in
just a second um so IRC in on Twitch all
day um last I kind of did that out of
order let's put this one here okay so uh
this is the biggest announcement today
is that there's only going to be one
book um i' I've toyed with the idea
about doing a book forever I only iidea
I only got behind doing the the idea of
a book recently U when I realized that I
can drop my subcast and I just have
Perpetual publishing which means that
I'm constantly changing what's in the
books um I mean yesterday I had a
separate Vim book the day before that I
had a code Mage book for beginners that
were under 10 and then I realized I
can't make a book that tells them to use
GitHub unless they're 13 because it's
against T terms of service so I changed
the target date for target age 13 as
soon as you change it to 13 hey guess
what people who are 10 years old are
different than people that are 13 you
probably don't remember that but they
are they're very different and as soon
as they start writing a book for
somebody who's 13 you know writing a
bunch about a bunch of wizards and code
mes and stuff is kind of lame actually
and so this has caused me to go back to
my original skill stack theme which has
has been my very successful thing since
2013 and that is hacker based in fact my
web page used to be a big Easter egg it
was filled with Easter eggs and my van
that I drove around it had a binary code
on it that was the first Easter egg and
everything else and so I'm going to go
back to that I'm going to go back to
using Easter eggs as a means to learn
and grow and and code and hack and the
theme of the book and the theme of of
whatever's left of skill stack which is
pretty much just me now is going to be
hacking it's going to be hacking it's
for Fun and Profit if you have to you
know imagine some you know evil AI
aliens from outer space make it to make
it okay fine uh but we're going to talk
we're going to joke about hacking your
enemies and all that stuff so uh I'm
also no longer streaming to the software
in Dev category um I've decided not to
do that again I just don't like it I'm
going to start streaming to the Science
and Tech category which is where I
started streaming which is where all the
hackers are and I'm going to start
running this stream like I started which
is the same way that I started skill SEC
which is as a hacker which is what I've
am I've been hacking since I was 10 and
that's where my roots are and if if I
sound a little bit animated and
passionate I'm a little mad at myself
for letting myself be sucked into this
like touchy Fey you know code magy
because I've never liked it in fact I
was reading my own book the other day
and I was going who wrote this and
then I realized it was me and I had
changed my voice and I was talking like
this stupid kitchy World of Warcraft
player and I was like this is not who I
am this is not who I am I love you I
love you guys please there there we go I
love you but it's okay here we go we're
gonna go hack power plants baby no we're
not we're not going to do that we're
going to talk about
it I'm G to show you what shod iio is
though on the first day of skill stack
the guys that were in my my two first
people at skill stack we hacked coffee
shop with permission and it was glorious
and it was amazing and everybody wanted
to do it and why did I why did I make
the change you know why because
yesterday I said hey everybody forget
about all this cool terminal Linux stuff
just skip that because we're going to
write code which code which is like way
down here at the bottom I said just
forget about that just skip all the
terminal stuff we just get a minimal
terminal up just run git bash it sucks
it's really bad you can't use t- or
WeChat or anything can't use RC can't
can't do mods can't do command line
anything on get bash but it's okay for
now because we're going to learn how to
code you know want know what it didn't
work you know why it didn't work because
Dale and other people are like but I
want the cool stuff and who doesn't want
the cool stuff I feel so bad that I let
myself think you know why you know why I
did it I did it because I wanted to get
to the go programming and every single
year we don't get there and the reason
is always the same there's too much to
do before we get
there so I I I'm going to try I'm going
to go back again though because here's
the reason you know what people want you
know what my community wants my
community you know what my community
wants they want to learn how to hack
they want to be good in the terminal and
they don't want to learn you know rooted
node trees and go they they want to
learn how to use just enough go to be
really awesome and make a
homekit or a rot kid or whatever with
Bonsai that's what they want they want
to they how can I make my scripts my
bash scripts faster right them and go
that's what they want that's what my
people want right and for some reason I
let myself change anyway keep going here
the biggest reason the biggest this is
the single biggest reason I did a whole
video on this I did an hour long video
on
this um programming is cool with the
terminal is also cool yeah they're both
cool programming in the terminal is like
the coolest right like where's
my is it not going to do it
my AI is my my detector my filter is not
doing its thing all right oh well I feel
I feel dejected anyway so I made a whole
video on wsl2 plus WSL U which has been
out since 2018 I feel really stupid
because I didn't know that my AI knew it
and she helped me out and she gos oh
absolutely you can do that so based on
that that means wsl2 is now in the house
whether it crashes or not I still think
it's unstable I don't care the wsl2 is
now the standard for Windows it is in
you know terminal velocity in the book
and in this stream that is now going to
be the standard Linux on Windows it's
also the standard Linux at Microsoft
people are reporting uh on YouTube that
it has gotten a lot better in the last
few years so it's not crashing as much
and obviously we can do GH off login and
all the things that are really cool we
can we can play our
clips of course that's a q
right we can play our
clipse wait we can play our Clips it's a
unic system it's a unic
system it's a unic
system so there so
there we can play our Clips we can write
code that plays Clips this is way more
fun than writing a
game anyway so that's now that we have
WSL we can do that you can do that from
Windows you can do that from a Mac now
and you can do obviously if you have a
Linux box so so the only backage we're
learning now there's no wind get we
don't
care we don't even need
it I wrote I wrote tons and tons of code
to deal with wiet it's all going away
the only code that's ever going to exist
in my code base is stuff that works with
brew and stuff that works with ap the
end and if you want to run red hat or
Pac-Man or something the idea that I
almost put
M2 which has Pac-Man even though it's
not really arched to download Windows
software on a Windows machine as the
standard thing in my book gives me
shivers now I cannot even believe that I
even considered that and the only reason
I did is because of all the things that
you couldn't do with G bash well guess
what you can do all of those things with
WSL 2 because wsl2 is legitimately Linux
running out of Windows so that's what
we're using so many people are like oh
my God you're such an idiot why didn't
you do that all along and I've told you
a million times why so I don't want to
hear it the reason I didn't do it is
because WS2 blew up above everything
else it was unstable and it blew up
we're giving it another try mostly
because it's got integration that I
discovered so so that's what's going on
with that we're making a video welcome
for the raid thank you for the raid um
I'll I'm just going to finish this video
here and we'll talk to you in just a bit
so uh so we're setting up what else are
we doing we're setting up get in
GitHub and the really great thing about
that is if you're a beginner you can be
able to GH off login and have it pop
open your web browser and do all the
good stuff where you type in your
authentication thing I've been doing it
all dayto day on windows by the way it's
really amazing uh so the next thing
we're going to do after that is we're
going to learn how to to clone and start
your own do files repo that's all that's
the same thing as what's in the book as
before the difference is that it's going
to be a lot easier because getting
GitHub is a lot easier AP install GH
that's it we don't have to deal with
wingit and all that crap uh we're going
to set up Bash that's just setup bash
we're going to you know take the bash RC
that I've get I created for you and the
bash RC file will get you started
but as you can see here you're also
going to learn how to deal with your own
Bachelor C later in the in the Boost or
in the in the book and then we're going
to set up westerm the fastest GP
accelerated terminal on the planet
that's not run by
idiots I'm sorry I had to say that West
term is run by amazing people that's
what I meant to say I really love it and
by the way I'm I'm done apologizing for
being who I am which is really snarky
and mean and rude sometimes I don't care
I just point I don't care because the
people who respond to me are actually
good people they know I'm a good person
they know I'm just having fun they know
I'm not actually attacking anybody and
it's a part of the Rob that you know
just turned 57 I'm tired of being
something else just for the YouTube and
we'll leave it at that set up bash all
right we're going to set up bash then
we're going to set up westerm I already
told you about that we're going to set
up um it's a leak code you have to do
leak code all day to pass interviews I
feel so sorry for you why we can talk
about that in just a second how come
lead code is so stupid and why would you
ever want to work for a company that had
a lead code interview it's completely
unnecessary there's nothing leak code
shows me except for how stupid a company
is okay let's move on set up
t-mo we're gonna set up t-mo we're gonna
set up t-u are you saying Google is
stupid yes that's what I'm saying and
with a big exclamation point okay so
learn Ed learn X learn VI vim and N Vim
unapologetically we are going to learn
the standard Unix
editor I am sick and
tired of having arguments with people
who set control C which sends an
interrupt as
Escape you're not worthy I'm not even
arguing with you if you think that
that's a good thing to do
goodbye goodbye I want to talk to the
people that aren't idiots all right
nextar t-u wait we got t-u on there
twice I guess we really like it we can
learn tmu twice all right set up WeChat
IRC and uh we're going to set up weat
IRC I already have a set up for that
here's the great thing though you don't
have to be a pro with IRC now to start
with WeChat IRC because if you have WSL
we can help you out I got a startup
script already for you and it just
prompts you you go plug your token in
there from you know twitch and you're
good to go you can start participating
in IRC with the rest of us it's going to
be great and then what and then we have
then we learn we chat a little bit how
to use it uh it's really really great in
fact Let me let me show you something
really cool about
WeChat I'm about to send you this line
right here I'm going to send this line
to the chat in VI without leaving it
there we go pretty cool right what did I
just do what did I just do I just used a
Unix filter from VI not even bimm bi
that passed it to a command on standard
input and passed it off off to a 5o a
first in first out pipe that WeChat is
listening to pretty damn cool right why
would you ever want to like screw around
with something else when you can learn
how to do that it's super easy it's
super easy you want to see the
filter this is it right here it looks
for the fifo the chat fifo and it writes
it if this looks like you know something
you don't understand hey do you guys
want that
code I can send you that codee
watch
this oh man oh
man I could not find it it's in my
script repos oh wait wa wait wait let me
see this I'm GNA I'm gonna fix write
some code for you right now so there so
there it says repos it says repo equals
B much repos has CMD I have to fix the I
I I broke this one recently all right
here we go B match
[Music]
I recently broke this this command now
I'll have to go f fix it again well
anyway demo syndrome yeah you know what
it did it tried to do it said repos
cannot execute required file line 42 of
my
repos oh there's a script that I got rid
of I deleted it this is a new
system new system who
dare anyway
so who this
uh we chat we talked about
that uh the command line web editing
with w3m and links if you haven't seen
that before you want to see that right
so what is
links we're going to go out and do an
internet search here you go let's go
read the Wikipedia from the command line
and then let's open it up in a web
browser because it has JavaScript or
something I did that with one command I
tapped the comma key you probably want
to learn that right I'm guessing you
want to learned that most people do
so um what else are we doing here here
we go you can use that're going to talk
about y3m or links they're both good
we're talking about how to do command
line searching with mods my mods is off
right now what is mods
oopsie my command line Cloud searching
is turned off right now we're going to
learn all of this terminal Wizardry this
is a thing and my rate limit's done I
need to get it I need to upload my rate
limit but I'll show you how to do that
um and then more stuff as well uh that's
not even the beginning we're going to
learn how to script and Bash mostly so
you can understand you're pretty
exhausted bash RC and then we're going
to learn how to code and go but we are
not going to learn computer science
we're not going to learn how to do link
lists we're not going to do you know go
routines other than to handle a thing
we're going to do basic go programming
so you understand programming and so you
can make wicked cool command line
utilities that include terminal UI such
as
Sunrise which is for some reason not
have millions of colors right now I
cannot figure that out probably because
I'm in a terminal it's like really weird
we we had this problem the other day
which we trying to figure out why it was
that it should have millions of col it
doesn't right
now and uh we're do breath we we we will
well that's all in Bonsai so we will
cover Bonsai and bonsai's got a bunch of
pre predefined things in there so you
can if you want to figure out breath for
search and why you would do it fine but
you know that's not going to be the
highest thing on the on the point the
main thing is if those people who want
to make you know root kits and home kits
out of on and go and go we're going to
show you how to do that so that and
we'll end with that we're going to end
with that that'll be the main last thing
but when you learn you know it's going
to take all the way to learning how to
bash script to be able to understand how
to read The Bachelor C that I'm going to
help you set up so this is you know this
is a bachelor C it's a pretty
complicated Bachelor SE it's got a l of
good stuff in here including oh I don't
know stuff that clones repos
automatically from the command line in
one command uh I could clone all of
Linux if I wanted to right now I won't
just with one command um take it right
to my thing so this is all terminal
magic uh that helps you move at terminal
velocity which is the title of the book
and I'm just going to own it I I I have
been putting off I try to rush everybody
through all the cool terminals stuff so
we could get to the go programming and
it failed it failed uh boot kit root kit
sh kit all of them yeah so we you know
my attempts to sort of rush everybody
through all the cool terminal tricks I
just showed you totally failed because
everybody wants to learn that and even
when they they say they don't and and I
say okay you're on your own because I
want to get to the ghost Tu they have
problems and they can't do it so they
the overwhelming consensus is that
people that are watching me people in my
community old and young you know Noob
and Veteran want me to do it all they
want me to do all of it even if it takes
forever again so what does that mean
that means that as of
tomorrow uh I will be working on the
other book and we'll be working from the
other book called terminal velocity and
you you know you can watch for that at
at the normal place and so the next
holiday boost will have that in there I
am going to put this uh video in the
holiday boost uh path because holiday
boost started out doing go coding and
now we we've taken a pretty substantial
side turn uh from that and we're going
to go back to this so if you're
wondering what you need to do next
because you're watching the Boost um uh
many years of just screwing around with
computers before the programmer thing
happened yes it's true so the the if
you're wondering what to do next on the
holiday boost install w L 2 and WSL U on
your uh on your um Windows machine if
that's what you have if you have a Mac
you already have Brew installed those
that's your main thing if you get to
that point you'll be caught up you'll be
caught up and I just going to change the
West term so it works with with wsl2 and
I'm going to change the West term so it
works with with mac and after that we'll
be right back where we were the only
difference is that we're now going to
talk about them neovim and t-mo and
those things will be in in the other
book okay so that's the end of that
video um come on in and if you have
questions drop in in RC if you have
specific questions thank you